Finding Aid for Center for Japanese Studies (University of Michigan) publications, 1948-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for Japanese Studies (University of Michigan) publications 1948-2009, 1988-2007
University of Michigan. Center for Japanese Studies.
(in 4 boxes)
2.5 linear feet
Interdisciplinary, area studies center at the University of Michigan. Publications include brochures and pamphlets, calendars, catalogs of center publications, flyers, newsletters, posters, press releases, bulletins and course catalogs, lectures, manuals, programs, and reports. Also contains bulletin from summer session. There are also programs which describe the U.S.- Japan Automotive Industry Conference. Also includes a monograph from the Series Michigan Papers in Japanese Studies
9748 Bimu C170 2 UBImul C170
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
Publications are received on a regular basis from the unit (donor # 3854 ).
The record group is open to research.
See the finding aid for the record group Center for Japanese Studies (University of Michigan) Records for an historical sketch of the center.
The Publications series (.5 linear foot) consists of two subseries: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
The Unit Publications series contains brochures, bulletins and course catalogs, calendars, catalogs of publications, flyers announcing lectures and mini-courses, lectures, manuals, posters describing the noon lecture series, press releases featuring Japanese film festivals, programs from the U.S.--Japan Automotive Industry Conference, and reports. The Center for Japanese Studies publishes a monograph series entitled the Michigan Papers in Japanese Studies. The Bentley Historical Library holds only one volume in this series-- Is There Enough Business To Go Around?: Overcapacity In The Auto Industry, number 16. It will be found under the heading "Monographs".
This subseries also includes a newsletter entitled Newsletter. The fall issue of this publication is published in both English and Japanese. The Bentley Historical Library holds a complete run of this publication from 1990 to the present. Prior to this publication the Center for Japanese Studies issued a newsletter, entitled CCS-CJS News, with the Center for Chinese Studies. This title was published from 1983 to 1989 at varying intervals. They also published the CCS-CJS News Update from 1986 to 1988. This was generally a monthly newsletter describing the various activities of the centers. For these newsletters and other publications about the Asian and East Asian Studies Programs the researcher should consult: the record group University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies. Publications.
There is also one issue of the newsletter entitled CJS Alumni News. This publication was published in 1981.
The Sub-Unit Publications subseries includes publications regarding the fiftieth anniversary celebration and the Summer Session.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Center for Japanese Studies.; University of Michigan. Summer Session.; U.S.-Japan Automotive Industry Conference.
Genre/Form:
Pamphlets.; Catalogs, Book.; Newsletters.; Posters.; Press releases.; Programs.; Bulletins.; Lectures.; Programs.; Reports.; Manuals.
- Publications
  - Unit Publications
    - Brochures
      - Bibliographical Series No. 4: Japanese History and Occasional Papers, No. 4 1954 (Box 1)
      - [Field Station in Okayama, Japan] in Japanese undated (Box 1)
      - General 1953-1999 (Box 1)
      - Japan at the University of Michigan: The Work of the Center for Japanese Studies, [1973] (Box 1)
        (includes Japanese language publication)
      - Japanese Studies at the University of Michigan undated (Box 1)
      - Japanese Studies at Michigan: Thirty-Five Years 1982 (Box 1)
      - Center for Japanese Studies, University of Michigan, fiftieth anniversary 1997 (Box 1)
    - Bulletins
      - 1948 Announcement of the Center for Japanese Studies, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
      - 1951-1954 Announcement Center for Japanese Studies, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1958 The Center for Japanese Studies and the Far Eastern Studies Program (Box 1)
    - Calendars
      - Brown Bag Lecture Series 1987-1989 (Box 1)
      - Brown Bag Lecture Series 1989-1991, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Brown Bag Lecture Series 1992 (Box 1)
      - Lecture Series 1997-2005 (Box 1)
    - Catalogs
      - Books 1991 (Box 1)
      - Center for Japanese Studies Publications 1988-1989 (Box 1)
      - CJS Books 1985-2008 (Box 1)
    - Flyers
      - Film Festival
        - 1996-1998 undated (Box 1)
      - CJS Film Series 1975-2008 (Box 1)
      - Films and Lectures 1996-2009, undated (Box 1)
      - Graduate Fellowship 1952-1963 (Box 1)
      - Japanese School of Detroit 1997 (Box 1)
      - Japanese Studies and the Program in Far Eastern Studies 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      - Mini-Courses 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Noon Lecture Series 1995-2004, 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Noon Lecture Series 2005-2007 (Box 2)
      - Occasional Lecture Series, 1997-2004 (Box 2)
    - Lectures
      - Modern Japanese Poetry by Donald Keene 1964 (Box 2)
    - Manuals /Teaching Kit
      - Image and Life: 50,000 Years of Japanese Prehistory, An Archaeological Exhibition, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Michigan Papers in Japanese Studies
        - The Japanese automobile industry: model and challenge for the future? no.3, 1981 (Box 2)
        - Industry at the crossroads no.7, 1982 (Box 2)
        - Is There Enough Business To Go Around?: Overcapacity In The Auto Industry, no. 16 1988 (Box 2)
        - Occasional Papers, No. 1-4, Center for Japanese Studies, University of Michigan, 195, bound volume (Box 2)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Japanese Medical History Outline 1942 (Box 2)
          - Japanese Studies at Ann Arbor and Okayama 1951 (Box 2)
          - The Work of the Center for Japanese Studies (Box 2)
          - Continuing Work of the Center for Japanese Studies (Box 2)
    - Newsletters
      - CJS Alumni News, 1981, 1983 (Box 3)
      - Densho (in English and Japanese), 2003-2009 (Box 3)
      - Newsletter, 1975-1976, 1990-1997, 2002-2003, 9 folders (Box 3)
      - News notes, 1977-1979, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Posters
      - Outsize 1978-1997, undated (Box 4)
        (in outsize box, includes Lecture Series and Noon Lecture Series and Film Series posters)
    - Press Releases 1989-1990 (Box 3)
      (regarding the Japanese Film Festival)
    - Programs
      - U.S.--Japan Automotive Industry Conference 1982-1990, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Directories
      - Center for Japanese Studies 1967, 1973/74-1974/75 (Box 3)
        (also list of University of Michigan Alumni in Japan, 1975)
      - East Asian Studies Faculty, Staff, Student Directory 1981-2004
        - 1981-1982 (Box 3)
        - 1983-1984 (Box 3)
        - 1985 (Box 3)
        - 1985-1986 (Box 3)
        - 1986-1987 (Box 3)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 3)
        - 1988-1989 (Box 3)
        - 1989-1990 (Box 3)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 3)
        - 1991-1992 (Box 3)
        - 1992-1993 (Box 3)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 3)
        - 1994-1995 (Box 3)
        - 1995-1996 (Box 3)
        - 1996-1997 (Box 3)
        - 1997-1998 (Box 3)
        - 1998-1999 (Box 3)
        - 1999-2000 (Box 3)
        - 2000-2001 (Box 3)
        - 2001-2002 (Box 3)
        - 2002-2003 (Box 3)
        - 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Sub-Unit Publications
    - Fiftieth Anniversary
      - Symposia 1997 (Box 3)
    - Summer Session
      - Announcement for Summer Session 1948, 1948 (Box 3)
      - CJS Film and Lecture Series Posters 1998-2008 (Box 4)